(銀時)まあ まあ まあ
落ち着け ぱっつぁん！
(新八)なんで ﾎﾞｸの代わりに
沖田さんがﾃﾞｰﾄ行ってるんですか!?
い… 今 新八って言いました？
(沖田)ｱﾝﾀが うららさん？
どうも ﾎﾞｸ 志村 新八で～す｡
(きらら)あ… あの すみません｡
し… 新八って…｡
Excuse me, are you Urara?
["Note from Urara" Please turn the lights on
and don't sit too close to the screen when watching TV.]
Hi, I'm Shinpachi Shimura.
Why is Okita on a date
with her in my place?!
Now, now, now, calm down, Pachi.
Uh...um... Excuse me.
Sh-Shinpachi...
Did you just say...Shinpachi?
["Sometimes You Can't Tell
Just By Meeting Someone"]
I...I'm so sorry!
す… すみませ～ん！
Older sister! I'm so sorry!
お姉さま～！ すみませ～ん!!
えっ じゃ… じゃあ
あなたが私…｡
Then, you're the Shinpachi Shimura who I...my
younger sister was corresponding with?
妹と文通してた 志村 新八さん？
悪気は なかったんです！
騙す気もなかったんです！
I didn't mean any harm.
I had no intention of deceiving you.
いやらしいこととか そんなん
一切 考えてませんでした！
I didn't have any lascivious thoughts
or anything like that!
ただ… まぶしくて
あなたの妹さんが➡
But she was so dazzling. Your younger
sister was just so hot, so burning hot.
あまりにも ｷﾗめいてて
ﾔｹﾄﾞしそうで➡
I was desperate to correspond
with a girl like her.
こんな娘と文通できたら
いいな って必死で…｡
考えてたら 写真とか
いろいろ やっちゃって…｡
Before I knew it, I had sent
her pictures and things.
I'm the lowest! The lowest, aren't I?!
最低ですよね！ ﾎﾞｸ最低ですよね!?
ごめんなさい!!
I'm sorry! I'll never approach
your younger sister again!
もう二度と
妹さんには近づきません！
I know.
(きらら)わかります｡
えっ…｡
わ… 私も わかります｡
その気持…｡
I know...that feeling.
Older...sister?
お… お姉さん？
I'm the one...who is the lowest.
最低なのは 私なんです｡
I'm the one who needs to apologize.
謝らなきゃいけないのは
私なんです｡
私のせいで みんな… みんな…｡
It's all my fault...my fault.
まあ まあ まあ！
よくわかんねえけど➡
Okay, okay, okay.
I don't know what happened here, but
there's no need to be so serious.
そんな深刻にならないでさ➡
Nothing really bad has happened
between you two yet, has it?
２人とも まだ間違いは
何も起きてないでしょ｡
ｵﾚは よく知らねえけど…｡
ｱﾝﾀが 陣頭指揮とってたでしょ!!
Although I wouldn't know.
You were the one who spearheaded
the whole thing!
まあ ｺｲﾂは 何かｳｿついたりとか
してたみたいだけど➡
Okay, seems this guy apparently
lied to her and stuff,
but it was just two young people writing
a lot of letters to each other, right?
ｶﾞｷが２人で
ｼｺｼｺ文通してただけでしょ？
ｱﾝﾀでしょ！
あの写真 送ったのｱﾝﾀでしょ!!
You're the one! You're the
one who sent that photo!
うるせぇよ お前は！
黙ってろ 卑怯者!!
Shut up, you!
Keep quiet, you coward!
Naturally, I'm going to give a word or two
of advice when my protégé is troubled.
弟分が悩んでたら そりゃ
ｱﾄﾞﾊﾞｲｽの一つや二つ するだろ？
As your mentor, and as an adult.
ｱﾆｷ分として 大人として！
ﾋﾏだっただけでしょ！
You were just killing time!
You understand, don't you, older sister?
ねぇ お姉さんも わかるでしょ？
You came today because you were worried
about your younger sister, didn't you?
今日は 妹さんが心配で
ついてきたんですよね｡
You're shy and withdrawn, but you came out of your shell
because you were worried about your younger sister, right?
引きこもりがちだったのに
妹を心配して➡
殻を破ってきたんだよ！
いい話じゃねえか｡ なあ 新八君！
Isn't that wonderful? Eh, Shinpachi?
そ… そんなんじゃないんです｡
Th-That's not how it was.
私 そんな大層な人間じゃ
ないんです…｡
I'm not so noble a person.
I...I...
(きらら)私… 私…｡
いやいや いやいや！
もう そのﾓｰﾄﾞいいから！
No, no, no, no, no, no.
Get out of that mode! Stop that!
やめて それ｡ なんか すんごい
悪いことした気分になるから➡
You might start feeling like you've
done something really terrible.
お願いだから やめて それ｡
I implore you-stop doing that!
Let me help you.
(きらら)
て… 手伝わせてください！
Huh? With what?
えっ 何を？
う… うららちゃんを口説くのを｡
With seducing Urara.
えっ!?
あっ!?
What?
Whaaaat?!
(２人)えぇ～!?
No, no, no, no, no, no!
いやいや いやいや！
何言ってるんですか!?
What're your talking about?!
いや おかしいでしょ！
It's all wrong!
We were deceiving Urara.
ﾎﾞｸら うららちゃんを
騙してたんですよ！
What's more, we devised
foul plans to jump her!
しかも いかがわしい作戦立てて
手ｺﾞﾒにしようとしてたんですよ!!
Uh...that's why...
(きらら)あっ いえ だから
うららちゃんを芝居とはいえ➡
what I'm saying is, even if it's all an act,
I don't want that to happen
to Urara, so please use me.
そういう目に
遭わすのは ｲﾔだから➡
私を使ってくださいと
言っているんです｡
例えば 私が悪人に さらわれて➡
For example, if a villain abducts me
それを うららちゃんの目の前で
助けるとか…｡
and you save me right
before Urara's eyes...
いいねぇ それ｡
いや よくねえだろ！
That's a great idea.
No, it's not, and you know it!
いや いいよ！
No, it is.
She thinks her older sister is lost,
向こうは 姉ちゃん
迷子になったと思ってるから➡
実は悪漢に さらわれてたとか
自然な流れで いいだろ？
so a villain abducting her is good because
it goes with the natural flow.
そうじゃなくて 倫理的な問題で！
まだ罪を重ねるつもりですか!?
That's not the point! It's an ethical issue!
Are you planning to add to our crimes?!
問題ねえだろ｡ 姉ちゃんが
いいって言ってるんだから！
No problem.
Her older sister says it's all right.
お前も少しは お姉さんの思いを
汲み取ってやれよ！
You ought to try to understand
her feelings a bit.
妹が楽しそうに文通してる姿見て
思うところあったんだろう｡
She must have her reasons after seeing
her younger sister happily writing letters.
Hey, Okita-kun, change of plans.
おい 沖田君 予定変更｡
[無線](沖田)は？
Huh?
うららちゃんには 何もするな｡
Don't do anything to Urara.
I'll play the role of the abductor and snatch
the older sister right in front of Urara,
ｵﾚが 人さらい役になって
うららちゃんの前で➡
お姉さん さらうから
お前は それを止めようと➡
so you try to stop me and attack,
but let yourself be killed.
ｵﾚに かかってきて
あっさり やられろ｡
ｵﾚが うららちゃんを
さらおうとした➡
At the moment everything looks hopeless
絶体絶命のときに
新八が現れて ｵﾚを倒す｡
and I'm about to snatch Urara away,
Shinpachi shows up and kills me.
"You're so wonderful!" she'll say.
｢ｷｬｯ ｽﾃｷ！｣と なるわけだ｡
Got that? In other words, you
go on normal dates with her.
いいか 要するに お前は
普通にﾃﾞｰﾄしてればいいわけだ｡
You're not doing anything
funny...to Urara, are you?
[無線]何もしてねえだろうな
うららちゃんに？
It's all right.
(沖田)大丈夫でさぁ｡
元々 ｵﾚがことを起こす前に➡
From the beginning,
そちらさんが駆けつける
作戦だったでしょ？
wasn't it the plan for him to come
to her aid before I did anything?
Now that you mention it, yeah.
[無線]そういや そうだな！
紳士的に ｴｽｺｰﾄ中です｡
I'm escorting her around
like a gentleman.
ようやく
慣れてきてくれたみてえで｡
She seems to be finally getting used to it.
Is that so? Then escort her like
a gentleman to my place, and...
[無線]そうか そのまんま紳士的に
ｵﾚのところまで➡
ｴｽｺｰﾄしてこ… あ？
おう ﾓﾀﾓﾀしねえで歩け｡
Hey, don't dawdle. Walk!
What kind of escort are you?!
どんなｴｽｺｰﾄ～!?
Eh?! You're no escort, you're
an S-cort, for sadist!
≪ｴ ｴｽｺｰﾄじゃねえだろ ｱﾚ!?
ﾄﾞＳｺｰﾄだろ!?
There's a delicious diner around
here. Want to go?
うまいﾒｼ屋があってな｡
行くかい？
≪何で 普通にしゃべってんの!?
Why're you speaking normally?!
≪何で 恥ずかしくないの!?
Why aren't you ashamed of yourself?!
Oh, here it is. The diner.
(沖田)あ～ あった あった ﾒｼ屋｡
≪ﾒｼ屋じゃねえよ ｿﾚ!!
That's no diner!
Darn, it's full.
(沖田)まいったな 満席だ｡
おっ １席空いてるか｡
Oh, one seat's open.
Urara, have a bite before we get going.
うららちゃん 食べてきなよ｡
ｵﾚのことは➡
You don't have to worry about me.
かまわないでいいからさ｡
≪これ 何ﾌｧｰｽﾄ!?
What kind of manners is that?!
≪ﾚﾃﾞｨｰﾌｧｰｽﾄじゃないよね!?
絶対 違うよね!?
It isn't "ladies first," is it now?
Absolutely not!
(じじい)いや～ いい天気ですな｡
My, what fine weather.
≪突っ込めよ じじい！
何で普通に談笑してんだよ!?
Tell him something, old man!
Why're you making normal small talk?!
Yes, it is. It's already fall.
ﾎﾝﾄっすね～ もう秋だわ｡
≪今の すごいわかりやすい
間違い探しだろうがっ!!
It's really easy to find what's
wrong with this picture!
あれ 沖田さん｡
あれ なんか変じゃね？
Huh? Okita?
Huh? Something seems odd.
≪そうそう それ！
えっ なに何 何かあった？
Yes, yes, that's right!
Huh? What? What is it?
Hurry up, old man! That's right! Tell him!
≪早くいけよ じじい！
正解だよ ｿﾚ言っちゃえよ！
Isn't that a new mole on your forehead?
It wasn't there before.
(じじい)おでこに
新しいﾎｸﾛできてね？
なかったよね ｿﾚ｡
Why're you noticing such
minute details?!
≪って どんだけ繊細なことに
気づいてんだよ!!
Even she hasn't noticed!
≪彼女でも気づかねえぞ！
もっと あるだろうがっ!!
Isn't there something else?!
Old man, did you, maybe,
change cologne?
じいさんこそ
ひょっとして… 香水変えた？
≪なんで
じじい香水つけてんだよ!?
What's an old guy wearing cologne for?!
What is the relationship between
the two of you?
≪ｵﾒｴら どういう関係性だ!?
It's...It's awful. U...Urara is...Urara is...
ﾋ… ﾋﾄﾞｲ｡
う うららちゃんが…｡
うららちゃん…｡
銀さん！
Gin, in this situation, instead
of putting on a bad act,
これは ﾍﾀに芝居うつより
沖田さんを ﾌﾞｯつぶして➡
I should squash Okita and save Urara!
うららちゃんを
救い出すべきです！
Shinpachi, don't be hasty!
≪あっ 新八 早まるな！
うららちゃ～ん!!
Urara!
うにゃ！
どおっ!!
ぐわっ…｡
(うららのﾉﾄﾞの音)
My god! She's been thoroughly
disciplined!
≪これは…
完全に調教されている～!!
≪完全に服従してるよ！
She's completely submissive!
You jerk, what did you do
to Urara in a short time?!
≪つ～か ｵﾒｴ… あの短時間で
うららちゃんに何したんだぁ!?
お姉さん！
は… はい！
Older sister!
R-Right.
助けて～ うららちゃ～ん！
Save me! Urara!
ﾌﾊﾊﾊﾊ…！
これは なかなかに
いい生娘ではないか！
This is quite a fine young lass.
She'll fetch a pretty penny!
これは 高く売れそうだ!!
≪見た こっち見た！
She looked this way! She
looked this way, after all!
She can't ignore the danger
her actual older sister is...
≪やっぱ 実の姉の危機は
放っておけな…！
ﾎｸﾛ ﾎｸﾛ！
≪また ﾎｸﾛかい～!!
A mole. A mole.
A mole again?!
≪ｵﾒｴらどんだけ
ﾎｸﾛ気になってんだよっ!?
You jerks! How much attention are
you going to give moles, eh?!
お前 何してくれてんだっ!!
What have you done to her?!
Before we even talk about making her fall in
love with you, her personality has changed!
惚れさせるうんぬん以前に➡
人格 変わっちまってる
だろうがぁ!!
Sorry. She awakened to her true nature
more than I thought she would.
すいやせん 思った以上に
覚醒しちまったようで｡
But anyway, if I tell her to, she'll
fall in love with anyone.
まぁ でも ｵﾚが ｢惚れろ｣と言えば
誰にでも惚れますよ｡
そんな偽りの愛はいらねえ！
No one wants such a false love!
(きらら)ご… ごめんなさい｡
I'm...sorry.
わ… 私 新八さんの➡
I'm no use to Shinpachi or Urara.
うららちゃんの
誰の役にも立てない｡
なんだろう 私って ﾎﾝﾄに ﾎﾝﾄに｡
What am I really?
I'm so, so sorry!
(きらら)ごめんなさい！
お… お姉さん！
O-Older sister!
おい 新八！
Hey, Shinpachi!
(近藤)そういや
今日って 新八君が➡
Come to think of it,
isn't today the day Shinpachi is supposed to
meet that girl he's been corresponding with?
例の文通の娘と
会う日じゃないか？
(土方)知らねえよ
憶えてねえよ そんなこと｡
How would I know. I don't remember
anything about that.
(近藤)うまくいってるといいな｡
１回 女ができると➡
I hope it goes well.
Once he gets a girlfriend, he'll become
more forgiving of Otae.
お妙さんのことにも
寛容になる気がする｡
(土方)総悟の姿が見当たらねえ｡
こりゃ 失敗したとみたな｡
I don't see Sogo.
I think it was a failure.
(近藤)総悟？ そういや そう…｡
Sogo? Now that you mention it...
危ねえだろ！
どこ見て歩いてんだ！
That was dangerous! Watch
where you're going!
す… すみません！
I-I'm sorry!
なんだ あの女？
Who was that woman?
何か追われてるようだったが｡
Seemed like she was being chased.
♪♪～
な… 何者だぁ！
攘夷派の回し者か！
Who are you?!
An agent of the Anti-foreigner Faction?!
車 確保しました ご主人様！
I've secured the vehicle, Master.
(沖田)よ～し よくやった｡
Good, well done.
ささ 旦那 早く乗ってくだせえ｡
なかなか使えるじゃねえか あれ｡
Okay, man, get in quickly.
She can be quite useful.
What're you guys doing?!
(近藤)な… 何してんだ ｵﾒｴら！
あ… お疲れさまっす｡
お疲れさまです… じゃねえよ！
Oh... Keep up the good work.
You too.
I didn't mean that!
Okay, let's get going!
よし 発進ｺﾞｰだ 姉ちゃん 追え｡
After your older sister.
勘違いしないで｡ 私が
お仕えしているのはご主人様だけ｡
Don't be mistaken. I serve only Master.
なに勝手なことしてんだ！
開けろ おい！
What the hell are you doing?!
Open the door! Hey!
(近藤)ああ～っ！
That's...dangerous...wait...stop!
あぶ… ちょ… 停めてぇ！
(近藤)うにゅにゅにゅ…！
It's dangerous, so wait...stop!
危ないから ちょっと停めて！
ﾏｼﾞで… あれ？ ｷﾐ➡
Huh? You're
新八君と文通してた 写真の娘！
the girl in the photo who was corresponding
with Shinpachi!
Why?!
なんで なんで こんなところに!?
Why is she here? Wasn't she
on a date with Shinpachi?
新八君と ﾃﾞｰﾄしてたんじゃ…｡
ちょっと勝手が
違ってきたみてえで｡
Looks like the situation has changed.
(うらら)ごめんなさい｡
Sorry. I wasn't the one who was
corresponding with Shinpachi.
新八さんと文通してたのは
私じゃないんです｡
(近藤)ええ～っ!?
What?!
お姉さん どこにいるんですか！
お姉さ…｡
Older sister, where are you? Older sis-
そっか ﾎﾞｸ 名前も
わからないんだ お姉さんの…｡
That's right, I don't even know
the older sister's name.
(近藤)お姉さんが 新八君の
本当の文通相手だって？
The older sister is Shinpachi's
real pen pal, you say?
ああ お姉さんが うららちゃんと
うまくいくよう➡
Yeah. The reason why the older sister lent
us a hand to make things go well with Urara
ｵﾚたちに手を貸してくれたのも➡
おそらく写真見て すっかり
うららちゃんに惚れてた➡
was probably because she couldn't
stand it when she saw Shinpachi,
新八を見て いたたまれなく
なったからなんだろう｡
who completely fell in love with
Urara when he saw her photo.
だが いろいろ邪魔が入ってな｡
But there was a lot of interference.
あてつけがましい
言い方はやめてくだせえ｡
Stop being so insinuating.
うまくいかなくて 自分を責めて
どっか行っちまった｡
It didn't go well. She blamed herself
and ran off somewhere,
騙してたのは
お互いさまだってのに…｡
even though both sides
deceived each other.
Sis, when she saw the letters,
お姉ちゃん あの引っ込み思案の
お姉ちゃんが➡
手紙を見て 新八さんに
会いたいって言ったの｡
that shy and withdrawn older sister of mine
said she wanted to meet Shinpachi.
きっと お姉ちゃん
新八さんのこと…｡
Sis must have feelings for Shinpachi.
(うらら)
つらかったんだと思う｡
I think it must've been hard on her.
そんな人の
恋の手助けをするなんて｡
To think she'd try to help him find love.
それでも
自分のせいだって耐えて➡
Even so...she endured it, saying it was her
fault, and that she wasn't of use to anyone.
でも 何の役にも立てなくて➡
自分で自分が 許せなく
なっちゃったんじゃないかな｡
Maybe she just couldn't forgive herself.
What about Shinpachi?
新八君は？
何も知らねえよ｡
He doesn't know anything.
知らねえまんま
姉ちゃん追いかけていっちまった｡
He went chasing after the older
sister without knowing a thing.
目当ての女
ほったらかしにしてか｡
Leaving the woman he
was aiming for behind?
理屈で動くﾔﾂじゃねえ｡
He's not one to act on reason.
目の前で泣いている
女がいたら➡
If there's a woman crying in front of him,
惚れた女ほっといて
涙 拭きに行くﾔﾂだ｡
he's the type who would leave the woman
he loves to go and wipe those tears.
そういうﾔﾂだ｡
どおりで ﾓﾃねえはずだよ｡
It's no wonder he's not
popular with women.
Then by now, Four-eyes must've
found that woman.
(土方)だったら 今頃 ﾒｶﾞﾈが
その女 見つけてる頃だろう｡
いい加減 車を返せ
公務執行妨害で逮捕するぞ｡
Give me back the car.
I'll arrest you for obstructing justice.
ｶﾞｷの惚れた腫れたに つきあってる
暇はねえんだ こっちは｡
I don't have time to be involved
with silly puppy love.
Sure you do. This dude's been
totally slacking off from work.
暇だろ ｺｲﾂは
思いっきり仕事さぼってたぞ｡
(土方)ｺｲﾂは
いてもいなくても同じなんだ｡
Whether this guy's around or
not makes no difference.
お姉ちゃん
江戸なんて初めてだから➡
This is Sis's first time in Edo. If she goes
somewhere bad and gets into trouble...
変なところに行って
事件に巻き込まれでもしたら…｡
(土方)知らん
事件なら起きてから言え｡
I don't care. Talk to me after
something happens.
ｵﾚたちは くだらねえ仕事こなす
よろず屋じゃねえんだ｡
We're not a bunch of lousy
Odd Jobs who do silly jobs.
(沖田)土方さん
それなら心配いらねえや｡
Hijikata,
you won't have to worry about that.
An incident just happened.
(沖田)事件 起きました｡
♪♪～
(うらら)ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
何やってんのよ！
ﾊﾞｶなことは やめて！
What're you doing?!
Don't do anything stupid!
(きらら)うららちゃん
見て あの たくさんの人｡
Urara.
Look at all those people.
As shy and withdrawn as I am...
あれだけ引っ込み思案だった
私が➡
あれだけ人の前に立つのが
苦手だった私が➡
As uncomfortable as I felt standing
in front of this many people...
こんなにたくさんの人の前に
立てるようになったのよ｡
I've become able to stand
before a crowd this big.
皮肉なものね
もう死んでもいいって➡
Ironic, isn't it?
Once I didn't care if I died, and it didn't
matter what happened to me.
自分のことが
どうでもいいってなったら➡
あんなに苦しんでたのに
途端に変われた｡
I was able to change all at once,
despite how difficult it once was.
私 結局 自分が
かわいかっただけだったのね｡
I guess, after all, I just cared
too much about myself.
自分だけが愛しくて
尊い存在で｡
I was the only one I loved and respected.
だから
人からどう思われているのか➡
That's why I was afraid to know
what others thought of me.
知るのが怖くて
傷つくことを恐れて 逃げて➡
I was afraid of being hurt, so I ran away and
shut myself up in my shell all the time.
ずっと 自分の殻に
閉じこもってた｡
いろんな人に
支えてもらっていながら➡
I had the support of many people,
自分は誰かのために
何かしようとも思わなかった｡
but I never thought of doing something
for someone else.
自分のことしか
考えていなかった｡
I only thought of myself.
I did the same thing with Shinpachi.
新八さんのことも そう｡
うららちゃんの写真を
送ったのは➡
I sent Urara's photo because
I was afraid of being rejected.
自分が否定されるのが
怖かったから｡
新八さんは
正体を明かしてくれたのに｡
Shinpachi revealed his identity to me.
私は… 私は 嫌われるのがｲﾔで
必至に隠して➡
I didn't want to be disliked.
So I desperately tried to hide it.
そのくせ 新八さんが
私を見てくれないのが寂しくて➡
Yet, I felt lonely because Shinpachi
wouldn't be looking at me.
うららちゃんに
取られるのがｲﾔで…｡
I didn't want him to be taken by Urara.
私 汚い｡
I'm filthy.
こんなに汚い自分 もうｲﾔ｡
I'm sick and tired of my filthy self.
Sis, wait a minute! Hear
what I have to say!
お姉ちゃん ちょっと待って！
私の話を聞いて！
Forget it! Just leave me alone!
(きらら)いいの！
私のことは もう放っておいて｡
There, you see?
ほらみろ …型の女は
話 聞かねえって言ったろ｡
Didn't I tell you that blood type
[bleep] women don't listen?
ｵﾚの言うとおりだろ｡
[Broadcasting content that may encourage prejudice and
stereotypes against different blood types is prohibited.]
I told you this would happen.
(きらら)私は…型です｡
(土方)やべぇ 聞こえてた｡
I'm type [peep].
Ouch. She heard.
(沖田)…型って
土方さんと同じじゃないですか｡
Type [peep] is your blood type, Hijikata.
どうりで最悪なはずだ｡
No wonder things turned out
the worst possible way.
Don't put me with the likes of her!
(土方)一緒にすんじゃねえよ
あんなのと！
Don't judge people by their blood type!
血液型なんぞで 人を判断すんな！
Hey, stop. They're sticking in her.
They're all sticking into her.
(近藤)
ちょっと 刺さってますから！
全部 お姉ちゃんに
刺さってますから！
死にます｡
待て 待て 待て 待て！
I'm killing myself.
Hold it, hold it, hold it!
えっ!? …型なのか？ ｱﾝﾀ｡
Huh? You're type [peep]?
…型は あれ
いいとこ たくさんあるぞ｡
Type [peep] have lots
of good points, right?
な？
ｵﾚに振るんじゃねえよ｡
Don't pass it on to me. I haven't
really even spoken to her.
ﾛｸに
しゃべったことねえんだから｡
Jerk! Aren't you type [peep]?
ｵﾒｴ …型なんだろうが！
適当に自分のいいとこ言えよ！
Just talk about your good points !
If I tell her, it'll be as though
I'm praising myself.
(土方)お前 ｵﾚが言ったら
自画自賛してるみてぇで➡
なんか変な感じになるだろうが！
お前が言えよ！
That would seem rather
strange! You tell her!
なんでｵﾚが ありもしねえ
お前のいいところ➡
Why do I have to dig for good points
that you don't even have?
発掘しなきゃなんねえんだ!?
Shameless jerk!
恥知らずが！
…型は恥知らずなのか？
Oh yeah-type peep have no shame!
That's right. Type peep have no shame,
(沖田)そうでさぁ｡
…型は恥知らずなんだから➡
汚くても やってけるでしょう｡
だから死ぬな～｡
so you could live on even if you're filthy.
So don't kill yourself!
説得になってねえんだよ！
Not helping the cause, man!
死にます｡
待て 待て 待て 待て！
I'll kill myself.
Hold it, hold it, hold it, hold
it, hold it, hold it, hold it...
あの あれ …型はあれ➡
Um, type peep are, you know, have bangs
that look like an upside-down "A," right?
前髪が…を逆さまにみたいに
なってるよね｡
That's a total reference to me.
完全に ｵﾚ限定だろうが！
っつうか それ いいとこ？
Or rather, is that a good point?
ひろがらない ﾊﾟｻつかないよね｡
ｼｬﾝﾌﾟｰのＣＭ!?
It doesn't spread out,
and it doesn't dry out.
Are you doing a shampoo commercial?!
おい ｺﾞﾘﾗ！ 何やってんだ！
ﾃﾒｴも説得に参加…｡
Listen, gorilla! What's the matter with
you? Help me talk her out of it!
Huh? Are you crying?
あれ？ なんか泣いてない？
いや 泣いてねえよ｡
No, I'm not crying.
いや 泣いてるだろ｡
泣いてねえって➡
No, you are crying.
I said I'm not crying. Shut up!
言ってんだろ！ うっせ～よ！
What's that?
あれ 何？
(近藤)いや 違うよ｡
Nothing.
No, it is-could you also be...[peep]?
いや あれだろ
お前も ひょっとして…｡
死にます！
なんでだよ!?
I'm killing myself!
Why?!
I didn't say anything wrong
just now, did I?
今 何も悪いこと言ってないよね!?
明らかに ｵﾚと同じとわかって…｡
She clearly jumped because she realized
she and I are alike, right?
言ってる場合じゃねえ！
旦那！
This is no time for that!
Boss!
ﾊｯ！ うあ～っ！
ああ～っ！
あ…｡
離して｡
Let go.
あなたが離さないなら私が離す｡
If you won't let go, I will.
で 新八に助けてもらうってか｡
Is that so Shinpachi can save you?
うららちゃんの目の前で ﾋﾞﾙから
飛び降りようとするところに➡
You jumped off the building
as Urara watched,
新八が来て
うららちゃんに いいとこ見せる｡
so that Shinpachi could come
to your rescue and look good.
そういうことだろ？
Is that your plan?
悪いが新八には
こんなｱｸﾛﾊﾞｯﾄはﾑﾘだ｡
Sorry, but Shinpachi isn't capable
of such acrobatics.
なんで ここまでやった？
Why'd you go this far?
す… すみません｡
I-I'm sorry.
飛び降りるつもりは
なかったんです｡
I didn't intend to jump off.
つい入り込んで
勢いづいてしまって…｡
I just went too far, and the momentum...
(きらら)ｽﾃｷな手紙だったから｡
Because they were wonderful letters.
新八さんの… 皆さんの手紙｡
From Shinpachi and everyone.
(きらら)皆さんで
書かれていたんですよね？
You all wrote them together, right?
わかるんです｡
I could tell. I've been writing
alone all my life.
私ずっと １人で文字にばかり
触れてきたから｡
(きらら)不器用で大ざっぱ｡
He's clumsy and unsophisticated,
でも 表情豊かで
不思議な ぬくもりがあって…｡
but he's expressive and has a
mysterious warmth about him.
新八さんのために 皆さんで
頭を悩ませて書いているのが➡
The letters all of you racked your brains to
write for Shinpachi seemed to convey that.
伝わってくるようで｡
あれは 私宛てじゃない｡
Those letters weren't written to me.
They were written to Shinpachi,
weren't they?
皆さんから 新八さんに宛てた
手紙だったんですね｡
My letters were always written to myself.
私の手紙は いつも
自分に宛てた手紙でした｡
I asked for someone to rescue me, for
someone to extend a hand to me,
誰か 助けて って｡
私に手を差し伸べてくれ って｡
without ever even looking
at the other person.
手紙の相手なんて 見てなかった｡
All I ever looked at was myself.
私は自分しか見てなかったんです｡
There was no reason to expect a
reply to letters I wrote to myself.
自分に宛てた手紙が
返ってくるわけもなかった｡
How strange it is.
不思議ですね… 人は自分のために
筆をとっても 臆病で➡
When a person puts a brush
to paper for herself,
her writing becomes timid and small,
小さくまとまった つまらない文が
できてしまうけれど➡
but if she does it for someone else,
誰かのためになら いくらでも➡
she can write wonderful words that
are stronger and more free.
強く自由な ｽﾃｷな文が
書けるんです｡
If it's not for yourself, but for someone
else, you can become stronger.
自分じゃなく 誰かのためになら
いくらでも強くなれる｡
Watching Shinpachi and everyone,
made me come to believe that.
新八さんと 皆さんを見て
そう思いました｡
Shinpachi made me realize
this important truth.
だから そんな大切なことに
気づかせてくれた 新八さんに➡
I wanted to do something for him.
私も 何かしてあげたい と…｡
差出人は不明でいいんです｡
It didn't matter if I kept the
sender anonymous.
私って わからなくても
うららちゃんのままでも➡
Even if he didn't know
they were from me,
even if he kept thinking
they were from Urara,
I wanted to keep on writing
letters to Shinpachi.
それでも 新八さん宛てに
手紙を書きたかった…｡
でも 届かなかったみたいですね
私の手紙｡
But...I guess my letters
never reached him.
おい｡
Hey.
新八さん…｡
Shinpachi.
[Tell me your name.]
♪♪～
[Next time, I want to send a letter to you.]
新八さん…｡
Shinpachi...
気づいて…｡
He knew...
とっくに届いてたよ ｱﾝﾀの手紙｡
Your letters reached him,
a long time ago.
Will you write him a reply?
ちゃんと…
返事 返してやってくれるか？
♪♪～
[It's Kirara.]
[We can finally correspond
the way we should, Kirara.]
♪♪～
(お妙)新ちゃん お菓子 持って…｡
Shin, I brought sweets.
Oh, he's napping. What a mess.
(お妙)あら… 寝てる｡
もう だらしないんだから｡
♪♪～
[Preview]
Two forces that have fought continuously
since ancient times.
That's right! The Dog Faction
and the Cat Faction!
Neither is good.
Neither is cute.
The next episode:
"Beware of Food You Pick
Up Off the Ground"
[Again, Sadaharu suffers a loss of appetite. A worried Kagura (and Odd Jobs) take him to the veterinary hospital.]
[There, they meet a mangy old dog, "Kintaro"...]